Noriel Valdes

Prospect Park, NJ 973-800-7639 noriel@valdes.dev

Senior full-stack engineer with 11 years of demonstrated technical experience showcasing a diverse, flexible, and pragmatic set of problem solving skills, an emphasis on collaborative mentorship and leadership, and a high standard of excellence.

Work Experience

Instacart | September 2023 → Present

Senior Software Engineer II - Caper Retailer Tooling Tech Lead

- Leading an engineering pillar of five, responsible for rapidly developing a suite of retailer-facing web tools for Instacart's Caper smart shopping cart.
- Designing, modeling, prototyping, and implementing multiple services with Spring Boot, gRPC, events sourced from AWS IOT Core (MQTT) and SQS.
- Crafting bespoke tooling to meet the specific loss prevention standards of supermarket retailers like Shoprite, Schnucks, Aldi (Austria/Germany), and Kroger.
- Coaching engineers through code reviews to ensure that architectural, integration testing, and unit testing standards are being met consistently.
- Mentoring engineers through 1:1 pair programming, enabling the team to grow continuously.
- Developed a workflow to manage offshore remote inspectors' real-time evaluations of discrepancies during customer shops with live video and computer vision, leveraging Temporal for scalability.
- Adopted the maintenance responsibility for legacy systems while implementing replacement solutions that focused on observability and future expansion capability.

Northpass | *March 2021 → September 2023*

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer — Integrations & Partnerships Tech Lead

- Northpass was acquired by Gainsight in July 2023.
- Led an empowered product engineering team of three, responsible for building and maintaining a suite of integrations between Northpass's Ruby on Rails codebase and our strategic partner SaaS applications.
- Implemented an array of services and microservices; leveraging domain-driven design for clarity and consistency; CQRS for scalability and decoupling; and Apache Kafka for fault-tolerance, reliability, and high availability.
- Migrated continuous integration for Northpass's library of microservices from CircleCI to Github Actions.
- Optimized Northpass's webhooks engine to ensure prompt delivery of customer event data during application load spikes while expanding its capabilities by connecting it to course enrollment and learning path events.
- Enabled Northpass's custom Salesforce AppExchange application to retain historical course progress.
- Created a bespoke integration between the HackerRank Academy and ChurnZero, using AWS Glue and Lambda.
- Embedded the Workato workflow engine seamlessly into the Northpass product, leveraging existing webhooks and APIs to streamline the development process.
- Leveraged Workato's built-in connectors to quickly release integrations that synchronize client learning data with Gainsight, Zendesk, and Iterable.
- Configured local development environments with Docker Compose, staging and production environments with Kubernetes, and continuous integration with Github Actions

The Vitamin Shoppe | January 2020 → March 2021

Senior Software Engineer — Front End Tech Lead

- Ported the suite of marketing tags on vitaminshoppe.com from Signal to Google Tag Manager on an emergency basis after an unexpected data flow interruption.
- Choreographed sourcing of updated technical requirements and data flow validation with internal stakeholders and external providers, as part of the tag manager migration.
- Led a team consisting of three engineers, a quality analyst, and a product manager responsible for upgrading from Angular JS 1.5 to Angular 8 without interrupting ongoing feature development.
- Implemented a hybrid module approach with ngUpgrade, allowing the two versions of Angular to operate in tandem.
- Built a NodeJS middleware between Aptos One (POS) and JDA (ERP) which converted the incoming REST requests to XML payloads that JDA understood. The middleware was deployed using dockerhub and kubernetes.
- Automated the aggregation of data for consumption by in-store digital displays, enabling the stores team to avoid needing a tedious manual data collation process.

The Vitamin Shoppe | February 2018 → January 2020

Software Engineer - Front End

- Maintained ownership over the customer-facing storefront of vitaminshoppe.com, ensuring that business initiatives were delivered on-time and adhered to specifications.
- Introduced Typescript to the front-end stack, providing instant validation of data formats being passed throughout the codebase.
- Converted the front-end application architecture from bare controllers and template-directives to reusable components and singleton services.
- Migrated the build process from RequireJS to Webpack, enabling us to lazy-load JS modules, CSS stylesheets, and HTML templates, thereby decreasing website load time.
- Automated the front-end build process, including enforcement of code quality standards.

Century 21 Department Stores | *April 2016 → February 2018*

Full Stack Software Engineer - eCommerce

- Implemented a web application with Angular 5 on the frontend and .NET Web API on the backend to facilitate financial record-keeping for a "Mystery Gift Card" marketing campaign.
- Realized a browser-based 360° virtual reality shopping experience for the 2017 Holiday Homepage Takeover.
- Combined a vast library of disparate web applications into a single Ruby on Rails site that integrated with Active Directory for single sign-on and access control.
- Developed a native iPad app in Swift for soliciting credit applications from customers on the sales floor, and used Mobileiron to manage the deployment of this app to 175 devices at 11 stores across 4 states.
- Created a product data management tool with AngularJS 1.4 on the frontend and .NET Web API on the backend enabling the eCommerce production team to complete a week's worth of work in less than 5 minutes.

Century 21 Department Stores | January 2015 → April 2016

Product Manager - eCommerce

- Managed the re-platforming of c21stores.com to Ruby on Rails.
- Documented all production and post-production workflows on the legacy Coldfusion platform to speed up QA.
- Facilitated the day-to-day operations of the Web Production team to ensure business continuity.
- Implemented several scripts and tools to automate the transition between platforms for business users.

Century 21 Department Stores | December 2013 → January 2015

Requirements Engineer — eCommerce

- Elicited business requirements from stakeholders.
- Formalized business requirements into specification documents containing a combination of functional/non-functional requirements, and UI/UX wireframes, mockups, and comps.
- Ensured that deliverables complied with functional requirements.

The Frick Collection | June 2013 → December 2013

Software Engineer -iOS

- Implemented a fullstack cross-platform mobile app with Adobe AIR in accordance with the iOS 7 HIG.
- Also served as Business Analyst and Project Manager for the team.

Education

Stevens Institute of Technology | *Aug 2013 → Dec 2017* **Master of Science:** Enterprise and Cloud Computing

Stevens Institute of Technology | Aug 2008 → May 2013

Bachelor of Arts: Music & Technology

Minor: Computer Science

Skills

Programming Languages and Libraries: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Angular, NodeJS, React, Python, Swift, C# **Engineering:** Test-Driven Development, Clean Code, Domain-Driven Design

Spoken Languages: Natively fluent in both English and Spanish